## Su Lin Blodgett

CONTACT Information

140 Governors Drive Amherst, MA 01003 blodgett@cs.umass.edu cs.umass.edu/~blodgett

RESEARCH INTERESTS I am interested in using computational text analysis to answer social science, particularly sociolinguistic, questions; I am especially interested in linguistic variation in social media text. To that end, I develop natural language processing tools that are fairer and more robust.

**EDUCATION** 

University of Massachusetts Amherst

Ph.D. in Computer Science M.S. in Computer Science 2018 - Present2015 - 2018

Wellesley College

B.A. in Mathematics

2011 - 2015

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE Research Assistant. SLANG Lab, University of Massachusetts Amherst. Sept. 2015 – Present Advisor: Brendan O'Connor. Develop models for statistical text analysis, with a current focus on mapping dialect variation in social media and quantifying social bias in natural language processing tools.

**PUBLICATIONS** 

**Su Lin Blodgett**, Johnny Wei, and Brendan O'Connor. Twitter Universal Dependency Parsing for African-American and Mainstream American English. In *Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)*. 2018. (Presentation)

Katherine Keith, **Su Lin Blodgett**, and Brendan O'Connor. Monte Carlo Syntax Marginals for Exploring and Using Dependency Parses. In *Proceedings of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL*). 2018.

Su Lin Blodgett, Johnny Wei, and Brendan O'Connor. A Dataset and Classifier for Recognizing Social Media English. In *Proceedings of the 3rd Workshop on Noisy User-Generated Text (W-NUT)*, *EMNLP* (Presentation). W-NUT Best Paper Award. 2017. (Presentation)

**Su Lin Blodgett** and Brendan O'Connor. Racial Disparity in Natural Language Processing: A Case Study of Social Media African-American English. In *Proceedings of the Fairness, Accountability, and Transparency in Machine Learning (FAT/ML) Workshop, KDD.* 2017.

Su Lin Blodgett, Lisa Green, and Brendan O'Connor. Demographic Dialectal Variation in Social Media: A Case Study of African-American English. In *Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)*. 2016. (Presentation)

Abram Handler, **Su Lin Blodgett**, and Brendan O'Connor. Visualizing Textual Models with In-Text and Word-as-Pixel Highlighting. In *Proceedings of the Workshop on Human Interpretability in Machine Learning (WHI), ICML*. 2016.

Honors and Awards Passed Ph.D. Qualifying Exam (Portfolio) with Distinction NSF Graduate Research Fellowship

May 2018 2017

Paul Utgoff Memorial Scholarship, for one student in machine learning

2016

INVITED TALKS

"Demographic Dialectal Variation in Social Media." Workshop on New Methods in Computational Sociolinguistics, Leiden, Netherlands. Nov. 2018.

"Demographic Dialectal Variation in Social Media." Summer Dialect Research Project, Department of Linguistics, University of Massachusetts Amherst. June 2018.

"Demographic Dialectal Variation in Social Media." Data Science Research Symposium, University of Massachusetts Amherst. Apr. 2017.

"Demographic Dialectal Variation in Social Media." Computational Linguistics Workshop, Department of Linguistics, University of Massachusetts Amherst. Apr. 2017.

Guest Lecture on Dialectal Variation in Social Media and Computational Social Science, Mount Holyoke College. Mar. 2017.

"Demographic Dialectal Variation in Social Media." CS Colloquium, Wellesley College. Nov. 2016.

"Demographic Dialectal Variation in Social Media." Data Science Tea, University of Massachusetts Amherst. Oct. 2016.

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

**Instructor.** Ethical Issues Surrounding Artificial Intelligence Systems and Big Data (Computer Science First Year Seminar). Fall 2018.

**Teaching Assistant.** Advanced Natural Language Processing (graduate). Prof. Brendan O'Connor. Spring 2017.

 $2018 \\ 2017$ 

Oct. 2015

## Reviewing

EMNLP, W-NUT (EMNLP), ICWSM, PLOS One	
W-NUT (EMNLP)	

## SERVICE AND PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

D	Panelist, UMass Graduate Orientation Panel	Fall 2018
IAL	Student Volunteer, ACL	2018
	Co-Organizer, Inaugural Male Allyship Workshop, UMass Computer Scie	nce Fall 2017
	Panelist, Mt. Holyoke Graduate School Panel	Sept. 2017
	Social Chair, UMass CS Women	Fall 2016 – Spring 2017
	Mentoring Committee Member, UMass Graduate Women in STEM	Spring 2016 – Fall 2017
	Student Volunteer, EMNLP	2016
	Participant, CRA-Women Grad Cohort Workshop	Apr. 2016

Volunteer, UMass Women in Engineering and Computing Career Day